Guide to the Furioso Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Contributor Correspondence, 1938-51; Series I; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  - Williams, Oscar, n.y. Dec 21 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1939-40 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1948-50 (Box 2, Folder 133-34)
  - "Y" general, 1949, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Yarmolinsky, Avrahm, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - "Z" general, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Zukofsky, Louis, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Unidentified, 1948-50, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 139)
- Submissions, 1937-51; Series II; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Series II, Submissions, is arranged alphabetically by author and then by title. Material with no identified author has been placed at the end of the series. Unless otherwise noted, all material is either typescript and/or setting typescript, unsigned.
  - ABRAMS, MEYER B.
    - Review of The Portable Coleridge, ed. by I. A. Richards, [1951] (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - AMIS, KINGSLEY
    - "Dirty Story", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - "The Crack-Up", n.d.
  - ANDERSON, FORREST
    - "and Backwash" (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - "Landfall"
    - "Rough Reckoning", n.d.
    - "Wash", n.d.
  - ASHBERY, JOHN
    - "Friar Laurence's Cell", [1949] (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - "From a Diary", [1949]
  - AUCOURT, JEAN
    - "Canto from a Pressurized Cabin", [1951] (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - "Foreign Travel", [1949]
  - AUDEN, W. H.
    - "Poem: Clocks cannot tell our time of day": holograph signed, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - BARBER, BARTON
    - "Notice", [1951] (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - "Soliloquy of the Alderman's Nose", [1951]
    - "A Version of Pastoral", [1951]
  - BARNARD, MARY
    - "Cool Country", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - "In Praise of Potted Plants", n.d.
    - "Road to Xanadu", n.d.
  - BARNES, ALBERT COOMBS
    - "How It Happened": printed article, [1950] (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - BARON, BEATRICE
    - "The Players", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - BATES, SCOTT
    - "Fables", [1951] (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - "Item", [1951]
    - "Matinee at the Regent", [1951]
  - BEACH, JOSEPH WARREN
    - "The Rubbing Woman", [1949] (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - BEAUDOIN, KENNETH LAWRENCE
    - "Recollections in Third Street", [1951] (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - BECKETT, T. A.
    - "Serious Talk Downstairs", [1949] (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - BENTLEY, ERIC
    - Translation of Bertolt Brecht's "Chinese Acting", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - BENTON, WALTER
    - "An Interlude", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - "Lullaby", n.d.
  - BENZINGER, JAMES
    - Review of recent poetry, [1949] (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - BERRY, JOHN
    - "Oiseau ou Feuille?", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - "Verses upon a Blue Bird that I Had", [1950]
  - BIRSTEIN, ANN
    - Reviews of "The Body" by William Sansom and "Mare's Nest" by Paul Griffith (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - BISHOP, JOHN PEALE
    - "Colloquy with a King-Crab": typescript signed, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - "Resurrection": typescript signed, n.d.
    - "Whom the Gods Love": typescript signed, n.d.
    - Untitled: typescript signed, n.d.
  - BOGARDUS, EDGAR
    - "Etude in C", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - "To John Donne", [1950]
  - BOOTH, PHILIP
    - "Homage to E. E. Cummings", [1951] (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - BOOTH, WAYNE C.
    - "Thomas Mann and Eighteenth-Century Comic Fiction", [1951] (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - "Toward a Definition of Synaestheticology", [1949]
  - BORGERHOFF, E. B. O.
    - "High Thought", [1951] (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - BRANDES DE BEDTS, RUTH
    - "The Undefined", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - BRANTLEY, FREDERICK
    - Review of R. B. Heilman's This Great Stage, [1949] (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - BRINNIN, JOHN MALCOLM
    - "The Late Summer", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - "Letter to Statues", [1950]
    - "Serenade in Pulse-Beats", [1950]
    - "Testament in the Fifth Year", [1950]
  - BROMLEY, PRISCILLA
    - "Legend", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - BROOMELL, MYRON H.
    - "The Nebraskan in California", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - BROWN, PHEBE HASKEL
    - "Fair Company", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - BRUNO, MICHAEL
    - "The Broadway Musical Comedy-- Once Over Lightly", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - BYRNE, J. PATRICK
    - "Frustrate", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 170a)
  - CANBREDE, S. J.
    - "The Novelist as Human Being", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - CARVER, WAYNE
    - "A Man of Fortune Greeting Heirs", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - CASSILL, R. V.
    - "Larchmoor Is Not the World", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - COATES, CARROLL
    - "Prophetic Encounter", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - "A Sung Print", [1950]
    - "The Young Novelist", [1950]
  - COGGESHALL, HELEN
    - "And They Were Unwilling to Move Their Legs, Which Were Two Inches Long", [1949] (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - "Considerable Research", n.d.
    - "Dostert Is Continually Searching", n.d.
    - "I Have Consulted", [1949]
    - "It May Be Taken into a Real or Improvised Dark Room", [1949]
    - "Under Certain Circumstances, Honey"
  - COMFORT, ALEX
    - "On the Hill", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - COWLEY, MALCOLM
    - "Fox in Flight", [1951] (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - CRANE, MILTON
    - "The Art of Omission", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 178)
  - CUMMINGS, E. E.
    - Biographical sketch, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - "Sonnet", n.d.
    - "Speech from a Play" (typescript, galleys and galley proof)
    - Untitled poems (group of four):
      - "when god decided to invent", [1950]
      - "it's over a(see just", n.d.
      - "life is more true than reason will deceive", n.d.
      - "if(among", n.d.
  - DAVIS, BOB
    - "The Discovery", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - DENNEY, REUEL
    - "Lucretius' Venus", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - DEUTSCH, BABETTE
    - "Departure", [1948] (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - DOWNER, ALAN S.
    - "Drama: Reviews", 1948-50 (Box 3, Folder 183)
      Essays for a regularly-appearing column in Furioso.
  - DRUMMOND, JOHN
    - "New Values in History": autograph manuscript signed, 1946 Jul 31 (Box 3, Folder 184)
  - DURRELL, LAWRENCE
    - "In Arcadia", [1939?] (Box 3, Folder 185)
  - EATON, CHARLES EDWARD
    - "I Hear the Affirmation of the Evening", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 186)
  - EBERHART, RICHARD
    - Poems, 1939-50, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 187-188)
  - ELLIOTT, GEORGE P.
    - "Poem about Myself", [1950] (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - "Reading Some Materialists", [1950]
  - ELLMANN, RICHARD
    - Translation of Henri Michaux's "Birth", [1949] (Box 3, Folder 190)
  - ELY, ERNEST
    - "A Preface to a Novel in Progress", [1949] (Box 3, Folder 191)
  - EMPSON, WILLIAM
    - Article on "Basic English", [1940?] (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - Poem: "Not but they die": typescript signed, 1939 Dec 10
  - EVANS, ROBERT ALLSON
    - "Seven-o'-Clock Whistle", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 193)
  - EWALT, MARY G.
    - "Marriage", [1949] (Box 3, Folder 194)
  - FAULKNER, WILLIAM
    - "Afternoon of a Cow" (attributed to "Ernest V. Trueblood"), [1937] (Box 4, Folder 195)
  - FERARD, NANCY
    - "Someone for Percy Brett", [1949] (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - FIEDLER, LESLIE A.
    - "Portrait of the Artist as a Young Minotaur", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - FITTS, DUDLEY
    - "Proletarian Poem": typescript signed, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - "The Swallows", n.d.
    - Review of Joseph Campbell's The Hero with a Thousand Faces, [1951]
  - FITZGERALD, ROBERT
    - Review of James Agee's and Walker Evans' Let Us Now Praise Famous Men, [1950] (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - FLETCHER, JOHN GOULD
    - "August 1940": typescript corrected and signed, 1940 Aug (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - "The Last Time": typescript corrected and signed, [1950]
    - "To a Schoolteacher", [1950]
  - FORD, CHARLES HENRI
    - "Pastoral for Pavlik", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - "Poem for Aglaya", [1950]
    - "Song without a SInger", n.d.
  - FORD, ETHEL
    - "Road Work", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - FRIEND, ROBERT
    - "Letter to E.", [1951] (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - FURBANK, P. N.
    - "Soft you, our airy thoughts grow stiff", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - FULLER, ROY
    - "Byron", [1949] (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - "Chekhov", [1949]
    - "Emily Dickinson", [1949]
    - "Rhetoric of a Journey" (2 copies), [1950]
  - GALLOWAY, NELSON
    - "Map", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - "The Shadow BIrd", [1950]
  - GARDNER, ISABELLA
    - "Folkways", 1951 (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - GOLDSTEIN, BETTYE
    - Epigrams, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - GOLFFING, FRANCIS
    - Review of Ezra Pound's The Pisan Cantos, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - GOODMAN, PAUL
    - "The Boy Extracting the Thorn", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - "Our Meeting, 1948", [1949]
    - Review of Mary McCarthy's The Oasis, [1950]
    - Two poems:
      - "Medea Superest", [1949]
      - "Theseus", [1949]
  - GORDON, AMBROSE
    - "The Alienist", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - "Discovery", [1950]
    - "King Brutus II", [1950]
    - Review of Ford Madox Ford's Parade's End, [1951]
  - GREGORY, HORACE
    - "Bluethorne Wears for His Shield the Candid Eye" (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - "What Bluethorne Heard at the New Year", n.d.
  - GRIFFITHS, R. L.
    - "Redeployment" and "Recruiting Song", [1948] (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - "Three Poems", n.d.
  - HAUPT, ZYGMUNT
    - "The Wake and the Repast", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - HAYNES, PAT
    - "Reg.Imp", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - "Röntgenism", n.d.
  - HEARST, JAMES
    - "Late Spring", [1951] (Box 4, Folder 216)
  - HECHT, ANTHONY
    - "Harangue", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 217)
  - HIGGINS, JAMES
    - "Lunch Hour", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - "Nightclub after Hours", n.d.
    - "To My Classmates", n.d.
  - HONIG, EDWIN
    - "Editorial Circular for a New and Already Defunct Little Magazine", [1949] (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - "Report on a Recent Tide", [1951]
  - HOWE, IRVING
    - "Sherwood Anderson and D. H. Lawrence", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 220)
      With: copy of 1951 letter to editors by Howe.
  - HUBBELL, LINDLEY WILLIAMS
    - "Family Portraits", [1951] (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - "Hour of Concern", [1951]
  - JENKS, DONALD
    - "Exile", [1951} (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - "The Orchard", [1951]
    - "Veterans' Hospital", [1951]
  - "JONES, JEAN-PAUL"
    - "The Poet's Life", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - "Two Songs", [1949]
  - JOHNSON, W. R.
    - "Metaphors at a Point in Time and Space" (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - "No Man", n.d.
  - KARP, DEBORAH B.
    - "Carmi", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - KATZ, ROBERT
    - "Films: Four-Dimensional Art", [1949] (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - KEES, WELDON
    - "The Clinic", [1949] (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - "Dead March", [1949]
    - "A Late History", [1949]
    - "Relating to Robinson", [1950]
    - "Round", [1949]
    - "Saratoga Ending", [1949]
  - KEMP, LYSANDER
    - "The King of the Rainy Country", [1949] (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - KENT, SAMUEL
    - "The Castle of Chillon", [1949] (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - KERRIGAN, ANTHONY
    - "...les poils d'or de ses aiselles...", 1950 Oct (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - KOCH, KENNETH
    - "The Courtier": typescript signed, [1950] (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - KNOLLENBERG, BERNHARD
    - Fragment of an article on Yale's manuscript collections, signed, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - KROLL, ERNEST
    - "Fugitives", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 232a)
    - "A Hampton Suite", [1949]
    - "Malaise", [1951]
    - "Riverside in May (The Potomac)", n.d.
    - "Rockingham", [1951]
  - LANE, FRONA
    - "And Their Voices Were of Frogs" (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - "Scene in Passing", [1950]
  - LAUGHLIN, JAMES
    - Two poems from America I Love You, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - LAX, ROBERT
    - "Look, I Play the Tiger", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - LEIPZIGER, DORRITH
    - "Portrait", [1951] (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - LEWIS, R. W. B.
    - "Homer and Virgil: the Double Themes", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - LICHT, FRED STEPHEN
    - "Rummel", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - LOWDEN, PATRICIA
    - "The Evidence of Agates", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 239)
  - LOWE, ROBERT LIDDELL
    - Reviews, 1949, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 239a)
  - LUCAS, JOHN
    - "High Thought" columns, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 240)
  - LYON, JENE
    - "The Specific Animal I Mean", [1950] (Box 4, Folder 241)
  - MACAULEY, ROBIE
    - "A Nest of Gentlefolk", [1949] (Box 5, Folder 242)
    - Review of Frederick Buechner's A Long Day's Dying, [1950] (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - MCCOY, PAUL
    - "Berlin Gallery", [1949] (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - MACDONAGH, DONAGH
    - "Dublin Made Me', [1950] (Box 5, Folder 245)
    - "Galway", [1950]
    - "Torca Hill", [1950]
  - MCGAHEY, JEANNE
    - "Old Cemetery", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - "Time and Place"
  - "MCGILLICUT, MANUEL"
    - "The Plan", [1949] (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - MCINTYRE, AMELIA SNYDER
    - "If Taken at the Flood...": typescript signed, [1950] (Box 5, Folder 248)
    - "Item": typescript signed, [1950]
    - "News Broadcast": typescript signed, [1950]
    - "Poem for the Very Young", [1950]
  - MACLEISH, ARCHIBALD
    - "My Dear Mr. Angleton": essay for the first issue of Furioso, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 249)
    - "The Spanish Dead": galleys, [1941?]
  - MAC LOW, JACKSON
    - "Alas, Poor Queen, So Soon?", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - MANDELBAUM, ALLEN
    - "Three Innerscapes", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - MARSH, WILLARD
    - "Minority Report", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - MAUROIS, ANDRÉ
    - "Un Art de Vivre": typescript with numerous holograph corrections, [1940?] (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - MEREDITH, WILLIAM
    - "Biographical note": holograph signed, 1947 Oct 24 (Box 5, Folder 254)
  - MILES, JOSEPHINE
    - "Harvest Moon", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - MILLER, TOWNSEND
    - "Poem", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - "Poem", n.d.
  - MIRANDA, EDGARD DE ROCHA
    - "There Is No Dream Where All Is a Dream", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - MIZENER, ARTHUR
    - "Nature Poem", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 258)
    - Review of Graham Greene's The Heart of the Matter, [1949]
    - Review of current critical theory, [1949]
    - "What Humpty Dumpty Didn't Say", n.d.
  - MONTGOMERY, NIALL
    - "Philomel's Wake", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - MOORE, MARIANNE
    - "Rigorists", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - "Spencer's Ireland"
    - "The Student", n.d.
  - MOORE, ROSALIE
    - "Driving by Night", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 261)
    - "This in the Morning", n.d.
  - MORTIMER-MADDOX, ANNE
    - "I Have Been to Eliot's Cocktail Party, But...", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - MOSER, ALICE
    - "The Prisoner", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 263)
    - "A Walk...1940", [1950]
  - MYERS, ROBERT MANSON
    - From Beowulf to Virgina Woolf, [1951] (Box 5, Folder 264-266)
  - NEMOROV, HOWARD
    - "A long long time ago, when I was a child", [1951] (Box 5, Folder 267)
    - "The Earthquake in the West", [1949]
    - "Four Sonnets", [1948]
    - "A Fable of the War", [1949]
    - "A Harvest-Home", [1951]
    - "High Thought": a review of Kenneth Burke's A Rhetoric of Motives, [1950]
    - "Reflection", [1951]
    - "The Second-best Bed", [1949]
    - "To the Babylonians", [1949]
    - "Trial & Death, A Double Feature", [1948]
    - "Virgin & Martyr", [1949]
    - Untitled first chapter of a novel in progress, [1951] (Box 5, Folder 268)
  - NITCHIE, GEORGE W.
    - "For Hart Crane", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 269)
    - "For Wilfred Owen", [1951]
  - NORSE, HAROLD
    - "Colloquy of Time and Place", [1951] (Box 5, Folder 270)
    - "Graduate School: The Lives of the Poets", [1951]
  - OBER, WILLIAM B.
    - "Elegy", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 271)
    - "Epitaph", [1950]
    - "Homage à Robert Louis Stevenson", [1950]
    - "Revocative Poem", [1949]
    - "Russian Roulette", [1949]
  - OLSON, LAWRENCE
    - Columns for the "Reviews" section, [1950-51] (Box 5, Folder 272)
  - PARIS, ROSEMARY
    - "Now We Know", [1949] (Box 5, Folder 273)
    - Columns for the "Reviews" section, [1949-50] (Box 5, Folder 274)
      Includes a parody of Truman Capote's Local Color.
  - PAUKER, JOHN
    - "A Discussion of Sea Surface Full of Clouds", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 275)
    - "The New Wrinkle: A Fragment", [1949]
  - PETERSON, DONALD
    - "Mr. Hartley's Diamond Jubilee", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 276)
  - POUND, EZRA
    - "Examine": typescript signed, [1939?] (Box 5, Folder 277)
    - "Ez' Autumn Message to Undergraduates": typescript signed, [1939?]
      Includes several epigrams.
  - PRICE, ARNOLD M.
    - "An Editor Rejects a Poem", [1951] (Box 5, Folder 278)
    - "Song", [1950]
  - QUINE, W. V.
    - "It Tastes Like Chicken", [1951] (Box 5, Folder 279)
  - REEVE, PAUL EATON
    - "Conversation with a Cannibal", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 280)
    - "Portrait of a Statesman", n.d.
  - REXROTH, KENNETH
    - "Five Earnest British Poets", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 281)
      Editors' introduction to a selection by Rexroth of recent British poetry. With: galleys of the selections.
  - RICHARDS, I. A.
    - "Yale--Bergen Lecture", [1940] (Box 5, Folder 282)
    - Note on William Empson: holograph, n.d.
  - ROBERTS, LYNETTE
    - "1940": typescript signed, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 283)
  - RODMAN, SELDEN
    - "Survivors' Report", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 284)
  - ROSENFELD, ISAAC
    - "An Experiment with Tropical Fish", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 285)
  - "ROWLEY, THOMAS"
    - "Phoenix Song", [1948] (Box 5, Folder 286)
  - SACHS, DAVID
    - "Concerning Ivor Winters, Who Foretold Hart Crane's Death", [1948] (Box 5, Folder 287)
    - Review of Henry Green's Loving, [1950]
    - Review of Selden Rodman's anthology 100 American Poems, [1949]
    - "Song for a Bride" and "Sonnet", [1950]
  - SANDER, DAVID
    - "Freedom of Choice", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 288)
    - "Rape Slayer Sobs at Inquest", [1950]
  - SANDER, JOSEPH
    - "After the First of the Fiscal Year", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 289)
  - SCHEERER, CONSTANCE ROSEBAUGH
    - "Science", [1949] (Box 5, Folder 290)
  - SCLARENCO, CARL
    - "Dialogue", [1950] (Box 5, Folder 291)
    - "Sunlight Falling on a Picasso", [1950]
  - SCOTT, W. B.
    - "Chicago Letter", 1949 Apr (Box 5, Folder 292)
    - "Clutter Counters Everywhere", [1951]
    - "Gaëtan Fignole: Pages de Journal", [1950]
    - Reviews for "Low Thought", [1949-51] (Box 5, Folder 293)
    - Untitled story, [1950]
  - "SECOND, LOUIS" (LOUIS B. SHAW, 2ND)
    - Two poems: (Box 5, Folder 294)
      - "Circus: The animal trainer", [1949]
      - "October's Hot Abandoned Noon", [1949]
    - Two prose poems: (Box 5, Folder 295)
      - "October 1862", [1950]
      - "Order and Fruitfulness", [1950]
  - SHAIN, C. [CHARLES EDWARD?]
    - Brief reviews, [1950] (Box 5, Folder 296)
  - SHELLEY, ROBERT
    - "Evening in the Park", [1951] (Box 5, Folder 297)
  - SIEGELBAUM, HAROLD
    - "The Listeners, the Questioners", [1949] (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - SLOCUM, WILLIAM
    - "In Memory of Jack Johnson", [1950] (Box 6, Folder 299)
    - "Jours de Fête", [1949]
    - "The Last Case: An Elegy upon a Private Investigator", [1950]
    - "New Verse", [1949]
      Review of the 1949 Library of Congress recording, Twentieth Century Poetry in English
  - SMITH, WILLIAM JAY
    - "Oxford Letter", [1949] (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - SOLOMON, RICHARD
    - "With a Poppy or a Lily", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 301)
  - "SOMES, JETHRO"
    - "Jethro Somes' Apostrophe to His Former Comrades", [1949] (Box 6, Folder 302)
    - "Jethro Somes' Autumnal Colloquy with a Dead Friend", [1949]
  - SOUTHWORTH, SHARON GAY
    - "Necessities and Burials", [1951] (Box 6, Folder 303)
  - SPENCER, JAIME
    - "The House and the Remembrance", [1949] (Box 6, Folder 304)
  - SPENCER, THEODORE
    - "A Kind of Agreement": holograph (Box 6, Folder 305)
    - "Contemporary Problem": holograph, n.d.
    - "A Poet to His Girl": holograph, n.d.
    - "The Promised Land": typescript signed
    - "A Reason for Writing", n.d.
    - Review of E. E. Cummings' 50 Poems, n.d.
  - STACTON, DAVID DEREK
    - "Gautemozin", [1949] (Box 6, Folder 306)
    - "Street Song", [1949]
  - STARR, ROGER
    - "Dawn of a New Day", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 307)
  - STEPHENS, LAMARR
    - "Schizophrene", [1938?] (Box 6, Folder 308)
  - STEVENS, WALLACE
    - Four Poems:, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 309)
      I. "Les Plus Belles Pages" II. "Poem with Rhythms" III. "Woman Looking at a Vase of Flowers" IV. "The Well-Dressed Man with a Beard"
  - STOLOFF, RUTH BRICKEN
    - "The Search", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 309a)
  - SWAN, EMMA
    - "The Cloak", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 310)
    - "Cradle Song", n.d.
    - "Ephemerid", [1950]
    - "The Noble Savage", [1949]
    - "Poem", [1949]
  - SWEENEY, JAMES JOHNSON
    - "Exile", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 311)
  - SWEENEY, JOHN L.
    - "Burd-Alone" (3 copies): appraisal of the poetry of Marianne Moore, [1950] (Box 6, Folder 312)
    - Note on Basic English, [1950] (Box 6, Folder 313)
      With: copy of John Donne's "Love's Deitie"
    - Review of Robert Greacen's anthology Poets from Ulster: typescript and page proof
  - TALLMAN, ROBERT
    - "Project for a Film", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 314)
  - TAMBIMUTTU
    - "Preface to 'War Diary'", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 315)
  - TAYLOR, K. P. A.
    - "Scholarship for an Athlete", [1949] (Box 6, Folder 316)
  - THOMPSON, DUNSTAN
    - "Circular Terror", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 317)
    - "Orphic Song", [1950]
    - "Prince Atlantis", n.d.
    - "Tarquin", n.d.
  - THORP, WILLARD
    - Review of works by Herman Melville, [1949] (Box 6, Folder 318)
  - THROP, MARGARET
    - Film reviews, [1949-50] (Box 6, Folder 319)
  - TOWNEND, GAVIN
    - "Mrs. Juno", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 320)
  - TREECE, HENRY
    - Four holographs signed: (Box 6, Folder 321)
      - "Poem", n.d.
      - "The Poet", n.d.
      - "Psalm Carved from Sorrow", n.d.
      - "The Word", n.d.
    - "Death Mask": typescript signed, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 322)
    - "Three Poems": typescript signed, n.d.
    - "Two Poems": typescript signed, n.d.
    - "The Winds of Love"
  - TURKAT, JUDAH M.
    - "Voeschanan", [1948] (Box 6, Folder 323)
  - TYLER, PARKER
    - "The Conceit", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 324)
    - "The Life and Death of a Wish"
  - URDANG, CONSTANCE
    - Review of Ivy Compton-Burnett's Sullivant and the Lambs, [1949] (Box 6, Folder 325)
  - WANNING, ANDREWS
    - "Interim Report on the National Poetical Effort", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 326)
    - "A Primer for Modern Poetry", n.d.
    - Untitled note on the effects of war on poetry, n.d.
  - WEIR, CHARLES, JR.
    - "Birds on Sunday", [1949] (Box 6, Folder 327)
    - "But Sir, What Is Poetry?", [1950]
    - "Omens and Seasons", [1949]
    - "Referring to Relatives", [1949]
    - Review of Richard Ellmann's Yeats: The Man and the Masks, [1949]
    - "'Why this is hel, nor am I out of it'", [1949]
    - "Works of Man", [1950]
  - WEISENTHAL, MORRIS
    - "Breakwater: Atlantic City", [1949] (Box 6, Folder 328)
    - "Maud", [1950]
    - "Ocean", [1950]
    - "Tolstoy at Arzamas", [1950]
  - WHEELWRIGHT, JOHN
    - "Ave Eva: For Antoinette Konikon", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 329)
    - "The Rude Armchair: For James Laughlin IV", n.d.
  - WHITTEMORE, REED
    - Columns for "New Verse", 1949-51 (Box 6, Folder 330)
  - WILLIAMS, WILLIAM CARLOS
    - "The Cure", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 331)
    - "Dear Whittemore": essay on propaganda in poetry: typescript signed
    - "In Sisterly Fashion", n.d.
    - "The Last Words of My English Grandmother": typescript signed
  - WILSON, EDMUND
    - "Communication", [1950 (Box 6, Folder 332)
    - "The Mass in the Parking Lot": 2 copies, one corrected, one signed, 1950
    - "Memories of Stedman's 'American Anthology,'1890-1910 Division": typescript annotated and signed, [1950]
    - "The Pickerel Pond: A Double Pastoral"
  - WITT, HAROLD V.
    - "Feline", [1951] (Box 6, Folder 333)
    - "Girl with Crowbar in a Delicate Seascape", [1950]
    - "In an Eighteeenth-Century Picture Gallery", [1950]
  - WOODWARD, HENRY
    - Review of Homer Ulrich's Chamber Music, [1949] (Box 6, Folder 334)
  - YAMAMOTO, HISAYE
    - "Yoneko's Earthquake", [1951] (Box 6, Folder 335)
  - ZATURENSKA, MARYA
    - "The Holiday", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 336)